# Habibur Rahman Shadhin

Sobhanbag, Dhaka 1207, Bangladesh +88 01554 322 707 hello@hrshadhin.me hrshadhin.me qithub.com/hrshadhin

# PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE

Highly skilled Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience and demonstrated expertise in software development and server administration. A fast-paced learner and enthusiast of new technologies. Capable of working on a team with people at all levels as well as working independently. Core competencies:

Software Engineering

Desktop application development

Server Administration & DevOps

Web application development
Embedded System(IoT) Application
Object Oriented Analysis & Design

## **EDUCATION**

Daffodil International University — BSc in CSE

August 2010 - May 2014 | **Result:** 3.18 out of 4.00

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Pathao - Software Engineer II

September 2019 - Present

- Develop highly scalable, secure & fault tolerance backend services.
- Deploy and monitor containerized microservice applications.

## Freelance - System Admin

August 2016 - Present

- Deploy & monitor various applications & servers(LAMP, LEMP, DB, MAIL, ELK).
- Deploy applications on private & public cloud(AWS, GCP, Azure, Digital Ocean).

## <u>Genex Digital</u> - Sr. Software Engineer

May 2019 - September 2019

- Managing difference servers(DB, MAIL, WEB) on AWS cloud.
- Do DevOps work for multiple teams.
- Migrating old project code base using latest technologies.

#### ST Solutions — Sr. Software Engineer

March 2018 - January 2019

- Investigated, designed, and implemented infrastructure migration from managed hosting server to AWS and DigitalOcean cloud.
- Manage a small team, architected & developed customized web-based applications.

## <u>ST Solutions</u> – Software Engineer

December 2016 - February 2018

- Developed various types of desktop and web-based applications, REST API.
- Deploy applications on the Cpanel and DigitalOcean cloud.

## Repto - Sr. Software Developer

June 2016 - November 2016

• Developed online video course & inventory management systems.

# <u>NutBoltu Ltd.</u> - Software Engineer

October 2015 - November 2016

- Defined, configure, and deployed embedded and web-based applications.
- Developed a web-based application using python(Django, Flask framework).
- Make solutions using embedded computing devices(Arduino, Raspberry Pi) with python and c programming languages.

## LumexTech Solutions Ltd. - Web Developer

July 2014 - July 2015

- Developed a web-based application using PHP. Like CRM, Inventory, POS
- Develop desktop applications using C++(Qt framework).

# **SKILLS**

Languages & Scripts: Python, Golang, PHP, Frameworks: Django, Django REST, Flask, Bash, JavaScript, C, C++ Sanic, AIOHTTP, Symfony, Laravel, Lumen, Slim, jQuery, Vuejs, Qt, PyQT

**Technologies & Services:** Git, Docker, **Database:** MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Kubernetes, gRPC, Celery, RabbitMQ, Jenkins, InfluxDB, Redis, SQLite CI/CD, ElasticSearch, AWS, GCP

Editors/IDE: PyCharm, PhpStorm, VsCode, QT Collaboration: Slack, Trello, Jira, Creator, Vim

Asana, Hangouts, Telegram

## PRODUCTS / PROIFCTS

#### CloudSchool

February 2016 - Present

Open Source [https://github.com/hrshadhin/school-management-system]

It's a school/college management web application using php and laravel framework.

- Designed & developed the whole application.
- Giving continuous community support on GitHub.

#### **Smart Card Solutions**

November 2017 - October 2018

NutBoltu Ltd.

A complete solution for university automation. It helps to maintain students attendance, library, canteen, and bus fare using student Id card(RFID Card) in real time. Technologies used for this product are Mysql, Python(Django and flask framework), C programming language for embedded device operations.

- Designed complete backend architecture.
- Write a web module for communicating with low-level c binaries.
- Build a C SDK to communicate with RFID card and reader for python wrapper.
- Done research about to develop the whole system with the web interface and hardware assembling.